let quiz=[
    {
      question: "Who was the first man to classify stars according to their brightness. Was it :",
      option: [
           "Aristarchus",
           "Pythagorus",
           "Copernicus",
           "Hipparchus",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "For what reason was the Schmidt telescope specially built? Was it to serve as :",
      option: [
           "a sky camera",
           "a radio telescope",
           "an optical telescope",
           "a solar telescope",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "The greatest distance of a planet from the sun is called what? Is it the planet's :",
      option: [
           "Aphelion",
           "Perihelion",
           "Helix",
           "Eccentricity",
      ],
       answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "How is the atmospheric pressure of Mars as compared to the atmospheric pressure of the earth? Is it :",
      option: [
           "about the same as the earth's",
           "about 100 times as great as the earth's",
           "about 1/200th that of the earth's",
           "half as much as that of the earth's",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "The planet Jupiter has a mass that is :",
      option: [
           "equal to the combined masses of Saturn and Pluto",
           "equal to the combined masses of Earth and Mars",
           "equal to the combined masses of Saturn, Neptune and Uranus",
           "greater than the combined masses of all the planets",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one of the following moon features is named Copernicus? Is it a :",
      option: [
           "Sea",
           "Crater",
           "Mountain range",
           "Rill",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "A typical galaxy, such as our Milky Way galaxy, contains how many billion stars? Is it approximately :",
      option: [
           "10 billion",
           "40 billion",
           "200 billion",
           "800 billion",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Refracting telescopes always contain which one of the following ? ",
      option: [
           "Mirrors",
           "Lenses",
           "Television Systems",
           "Film",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "A comet's tail points in which direction ?",
      option: [
           "toward the sun",
           "toward the earth",
           "behind the comet in its orbit",
           "away from the sun",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Spectral line splitting due to the influence of magnetic fields is :",
      option: [
           "Boltzmann Effect",
           "Zeeman Effect",
           "Planck Effect",
           "Zanstra's Effect",
      ],
      answer: 2 ,
    },
    {
      question: "The Study of the Origin and evolution of the universe is known as :",
      option: [
      "Tomography",
      "Cystoscopy",
      "Cryology",
      "Cosmology",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "what % of the Sun mass has been Converted to energy ?",
      option: [
      "50 %",
      "1 %",
      "2%",
      "0.001 %",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "According To Kepler Law , the cube of the mean distance of a Planet from the Sun is proportional to the :",
      option: [
      "Area that is Swept out",
      "Cube of the period",
      "Square of the period",
      "Fourth power of the mean distance",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "According to Kepler Laws, all orbits of the Planets are :",
      option: [
      "Ellipse",
      "Parabola",
      "Hyperbola",
      "Square",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "In our Solar System which Planet has a Moon closest to its own ?",
      option: [
      "Earth",
      "Mars",
      "Jupiter",
      "Pluto",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
  question: "A Pulsar is actually a : ",
  option: [
  "Black Hole",
  "White Dwarf",
  "Red giant",
  "Neutron Star",
  ],
  answer: 4, 
},

    ]
